<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Laziness | (YurikoEX) => logger.Write()]]></title>
  <link href="http://YurikoEX.github.io/blog/categories/laziness/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://YurikoEX.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-30T13:48:52-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://YurikoEX.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joshua Taylor Lunsford]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[yurikoex@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning to Ride]]></title>
    <link href="http://YurikoEX.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/learning-to-ride/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-28T12:54:12-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://YurikoEX.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/learning-to-ride</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So this is my first blog post since the days of Live Journals and Buzz. I was just as much of a computer nerd then as I am now, albeit less driven and focused.
10 years ago I was programming PHP and hating it.
Making countless false start projects.
Having big ideas but too many distractions.</p>

<p>Now I&rsquo;m in a great place, programmatically speaking. I&rsquo;ve been developing since 2001, professionally since 2003, now with a new year starting a 13 year hardened wizard of code. If every year was a new level in D&amp;D I would be 13th level. That comes with a shit ton of hit points, a decent armor class, a shit ton of spells, and enough magic items to fill a room. I should be able to hold my own solo or really round out a bad-ass party. So what kind of adventures have I had?</p>

<p>To continue the D&amp;D reference, I have been slaving away creating automatons for Fortune 50 kingdoms during the day, then exploring the magical forests of technology at night. I believe the discoveries I have made in both places have had equal influence over my progression through the years.</p>

<p>While creating my first couple of a projects as a professional, I had some big ideas, dreams. The first of these dreams never died off. I was creating websites with PHP or C# as the server side stack, and HTML/JS as the client side stack. Even back in 2003, I wanted one stack to rule them all! VB6 windows applications gave you this, why didn&rsquo;t the web? Well I created countless &ldquo;Web Apps&rdquo; using different stacks, hoped Silverlight would be the answer, but quickly realized any NPAPI like plugin is dying and is not the answer. In 2008, JavaScript was gaining serious speed advantages in the browsers and this was sparking my interest in exploring the forests yet again.</p>

<p>My applications started abandoning server side rendering for templates and partials. It seemed the rest of the world was with me as JavaScript libraries evolved towards fatter clients. Then just as my javascript love was blossoming, a bright light appeared in the forest&hellip;. Node.js!</p>

<p>So for the past three years I have lived a duel life. Developing C# automation goodness during the day&hellip; and tinkering with Node.js at night. And this life style will surely continue until I kick off my super awesome project that will change the world&hellip;. but until then&hellip; a bit about me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m currently a lead IT developer for a big company. I specialize in System Center automation, mainly because I have been doing it for so long it feels like a specialty. Anything windows related is my bag. Feel free to read the full ramblings at <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/jtlunsford/">LinkedIn</a>.</p>

<p>Now my true passion is Node.js. And I have the honor of working on a side project with a great developer, Tyson Hester. I&rsquo;m sure I will mention him quite a bit as we work with each other nightly creating interesting code.</p>

<p>Our recent work includes a server-side octree for spatial memory management, integrating my <a href="https://github.com/YurikoEX/TinyMassive">Tiny-Massive</a> project into a larger system, and beating our heads against the wall looking for memory leaks.</p>

<p>P.S. The reason this blog is titled &ldquo;Learning to Ride&rdquo; is inspired from Ryan Macklin&rsquo;s post <a href="http://ryanmacklin.com/2013/12/getting-back-on-the-creative-horse/">Getting back on the creative horse</a>. While this blog is less about creative writing, just writing in general feels good and expressing all these crazy ideas may hopefully benefit others.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
